我刚在书上看到一个实验
I just read about an experiment
为测试是否能让两个人
designed to see if you could make two people fall
在几小时内爱上彼此而设
in love in a matter of hours.
听起来不太对啊
That doesn't sound right.
我的研究结果显示  这需要3到5年的
My research has shown that it takes three to five years
厚脸皮苦求
of shameless begging.
亲爱的  这事说出来  咱俩都不光彩
Honey, neither of us comes off good in that story.
我  我...
Yeah, I-I...
我有看到你说的那篇文章
I saw that article you're talking about.
参与者互问对方一系列
Uh, the participants ask each other a series of questions
能增加亲密度的问题
designed to promote intimacy.
在最后结束前
And then they finish it off by staring
还要凝视彼此双眼四分钟
into each other's eyes for four minutes.
这真是狗屁不通
Oh, that's nonsense.
我敢说我爱你
I proclaimed my love for you.
可上一次我看着你的双眼
And the last time I looked into your eyes
是因为你觉得自己得了结膜炎
was when you thought you had conjunctivitis.
虽然我的确是得了结膜炎
Other than the fact that I had it,
但那也真是个浪漫之夜啊
that was a magical night.
拉杰  你会跟艾米丽做这样的实验吗
Raj, would you ever try an experiment like that with Emily?
我才不需要靠科学来赢得她芳心
What? I don't need science to win her heart.
有我家的钱就够了
I have my family's wealth for that.
相信我  几个小时是无法造就爱的吧
I'm telling you, you can't create love in a few hours.
-对吧  -话别说太满
- Right? - Oh, careful.
你这是在质疑整个《非诚勿扰》节目核心
You're poking at the whole foundation of The Bachelor.
我们不需要在这上面辩论啊
Yeah, but we don't have to debate this.
我们是科学家
We're scientists.
我们能自己做实验
We can conduct our own research.
我提议我们囚禁两个流浪汉
Yeah, I propose that we imprison two street people.
-不行  -然后...
- No. - And...
你都还没让我说完呢
You didn't even let me finish.
别闹了
Forget it!
所以你爱咋实验猩猩就咋实验
So, you can experiment on all the apes you want.
但如果是我想操控两个被囚禁人类的情绪
But I want to manipulate the emotions of two captive human beings,
我就瞬间成了大魔王是吗
suddenly I'm the monster.
为什么你不自己做这测试呢
Why don't you just do the test?
为了科学  我很乐意
In the interest of science, I'd be willing to.
什么  你会愿意接受一场你得回答
What? You're okay with an experiment where you have
最深层内心想法的尴尬问题的实验吗
to answer awkward questions about your innermost feelings?
是啊
Yes.
拜托拜托  让我跟他做这实验
Please, can I do it with him? Please?!
我听了谢尔顿对人事物的感受足足十年了
I've been listening to Sheldon's feelings on things for ten years.
换人  你上场吧
Tag, you're it.
万一实验成功了怎么办
Yeah, but what if the experiment works?
我不会爱上谢尔顿
I'm not gonna fall in love with Sheldon.
我当年也这么说
That's what I said.
结果他以迅雷不及掩耳之势
Before I knew it, he pontificated his way
霸道地侵占了我的心
right into my heart.
有趣小知识  "霸道"
Uh, fun fact-- "pontificate"
是来自拉丁文里的"教皇"
comes from the Latin word "pontifex,"
有着"造桥人"或"教皇"的意思
which means "bridge builder" or "pope."
爱上了吗
In love yet?
佩妮  我就好奇
Just out of curiosity, Penny,
如果这个实验真让我们坠入了爱河
if this experiment does make us fall in love,
你会愿意载我去威斯康星州的日内瓦湖城
would you drive me to Lake Geneva, Wisconsin
参加加里大会吗
for Gary Con?
这是唯一一个庆祝
It's the only convention celebrating
加里·吉盖克斯的一生与成就的大会
the life and work of Gary Gygax,
他是《龙与地下城》[桌游]的创始者之一
the co-creator of Dungeons and Dragons.
其实呢  我诚心告诉你
You know what? I can honestly say
如果我们爱上对方  我不止会载你去那里
if we fall in love, not only will I drive you there,
我还会买所有你想要的龙T恤给你
I will buy you all the dragon T-shirts you want.
来吧  宝贝儿  咱们来吧
Okay, babe, let's do this.
你们真的能这么冷静面对
You guys are really being calm
佩妮与谢尔顿做这个实验的事吗
about Penny and Sheldon doing this thing.
如果我是你们
If it were me,
我就会有点紧张
I-I'd be a little nervous.
为什么
Why?
就算那研究只是胡扯
Well, even if the study's nonsense,
我这个人还是不敢拼人品
I-I don't believe in tempting fate.
所以我也不愿意用碟仙板
Same reason I wouldn't use a Ouija board,
或者招惹亚洲人
or pick a fight with an Asian guy.
虽然他应该不会空手道  但是...
He probably doesn't know karate, but...
干嘛冒险呢
why risk it?
我想我们没啥好担心的
I think we're safe.
李小龙高中里的小混混也是这么想啊
Well, that's what the bullies at Bruce Lee's high school thought.
结果咧  哇哒
And then, bam!
空手道
Karate.
我们就干坐在这里等他们做完实验吗
Well, are we just gonna sit here while they do the experiment?
我跟你也可以做啊
The two of us could do it.
行啊  应该挺好玩的
Yeah, sure, that might be fun.
第一个问题是什么
What's the first question?
稍等
Hang on.
好的
Okay.
"如果可以跟世上任何人共进晚餐
"Given the choice of anyone in the world,
你会选择谁呢"
whom would you want as a dinner guest?"
我真心会选佩妮
I can honestly say Penny.
那我会选清洁工
Then I choose a janitor.
因为我要吐了
'Cause I'm about to throw up.
我恋爱了
I'm in love.
来做点别的吧
Let's do something else.
艾米丽快下班了
Ooh, uh, Emily gets off work soon.
我们四个人可以一起出去玩啊
Why don't the four of us go out?
-行啊  -听起来不错
- Okay. - Sounds good.
我们要打电话问问霍华德跟伯纳黛特吗
Should we call Howard and Bernadette?
我不知道他们什么时候下机
I don't know what time their plane gets in,
不过我发条短信问问看吧
but let me, let me shoot them a text.
他有说葬礼怎么样吗
Did he say anything about the funeral?
没怎么说  不过感觉他挺好的
Not much, but he seemed to be in a pretty good place.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?!
你们居然把我妈的骨灰弄丢了
You lost my mother's ashes?!
不是  我只是说有时候行李会被转错地方
No, I-I'm just saying that sometimes bags are misrouted.
好吧  行  那这世上
All right, fine. Where did you misroute
唯一爱过我的女人被转错去哪了
the only woman who ever loved me?
第一个  我是说第一个爱我
The first... well, first, I meant first.
我需要一些信息
I just need some information.
航班号是多少
Uh, what's the flight number?
816.
我真的是指第一个
I really did mean first.
别说了
Just drop it.
你能描述一下那个行李吗
And can you describe the bag?
是黑色的
Um, well, it's, uh, black.
把手上系有红色缎带
There's a red ribbon tied to the handle...
世界上最伟大的妈妈就在放鞋的隔层里
The world's greatest mom is in the shoe compartment!
准备好开始了吗
You ready to begin?
好了  马上过来
Yup. Be right there.
我猜不用给你倒酒了吧
I assume you don't want wine.
正确
Correct.
在操作重型机械时
You're not supposed to drink alcohol
千万不能喝酒
when operating heavy machinery.
什么重型机械
What heavy machinery?
开始吧
Let's just start.
作为一名德州的绅士
Well, as a Texas gentleman,
我会倾向于女士优先
I'm inclined to say ladies first.
虽然我担心我这么有礼貌这么有魅力
Although, I'm concerned that level of politeness and charm
可能会导致你在测试没开始之前就爱上我
might make you fall in love with me before the test even begins.
要不我们扔硬币决定吧
Perhaps we should flip a coin.
或者如果你会玩
Or if you're familiar with the rules
-剪刀石头布也行  -问题一
- of Rock, Paper, Scissors... - Question one.
"如果可以跟世上任何人共进晚餐
"Given the choice of anyone in the world,
你会选择谁呢
whom would you want as a dinner guest?"
活的还是死的
Living or dead?
上面只说"世上任何人"
Just says "Anyone in the world."
我猜应该是活的吧
I guess that means living.
那也无妨
Ah, that's just as well.
尽管我非常想见欧几里得[古希腊数学家]
As much as I'd love to meet Euclid--
几何证明的发明者
inventor of the geometric proof--
他很可能穿着拖鞋[当年穿着]
he probably wore sandals
我吃饭时可不想看到脚趾
and I cannot look at toes during dinner.
我想到了
Oh, I know!
我最想共进晚餐的人就是
The person I'd most like to have dinner with
我自己
is myself.
你确定这个选择吗
You sure that's your choice?
因为我可是跟"他"吃过饭哦
'Cause I've had that dinner.
我还没有
Well, I haven't.
人们常说不要跟自己的英雄见面
And while they say never meet your heroes,
但我不觉得我会让人失望
I just don't see how I could disappoint.
你会选择谁
Who would you choose?
小罗伯特·唐尼[演员]
Robert Downey, Jr.
你...
You...
我没想到钢铁侠
I didn't think of Iron Man.
或许我和自己共进晚餐后
You know, maybe after myself and I have dinner,
可以找你们一起吃个甜点
we can meet you two for dessert.
你们俩想做点什么
So, what do you guys want to do?
我们俩是跟屁虫  你们定吧
Well, we're the ones tagging along, you pick.
你们玩过密室逃脱游戏吗
Have you ever been to an escape room?
那是什么
Mm-mm, what's that?
有点像互动式剧场
Um... it's kind of like interactive theater,
不过为了逃出密室
except you have to solve puzzles
你必须在规定时间内解出谜题
in a certain amount of time to get out.
市中心有一间
There's one downtown where
把人和一个僵尸关在一起
they trap you in a room with a zombie.
有点像现在佩妮的处境嘛
So, kind of like what's happening with Penny right now.
"你心中最完美的一天
"What would constitute
是做哪些事呢"
a perfect day for you?"
这个嘛
Uh, well...
我很可能睡个懒觉  做做瑜伽
I'd probably sleep in, do a little yoga,
然后去海滩上躺着
then lie on the beach while
有帅气的小伙子给我端喝的
cute cabana boys brought me drinks and...
可能会去做按摩
probably get a massage
晚上跳跳舞来结束这完美的一天
and then cap off the night with some dancing.
就这样吗
That's it?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah, why?
你完全没提到莱纳德
You didn't mention Leonard.
他也在啊
He's there.
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
莱纳德受不了瑜伽
Leonard can't stand yoga,
海滩  按摩或跳舞
the beach, massages or dancing.
他带了书在一边看  行了吗
Yeah, well, he brought a book, okay?
你的答案是什么
What's yours?
我早上醒来
Uh, I wake up.
享用了浇上黄油和枫糖的法式吐司
Uh, I enjoy some French toast with butter and syrup.
然后一个虫洞打开
Uh, then a wormhole opens,
带我穿越到数百万年后的未来
and whisks me millions of years into the future
用我超群的智慧去拯救
where my towering intellect is used to save
掠夺成性的外星种族残害下
the last remnants of mankind
最后一名人类
from a predatory alien race.
奇怪  你也没提艾米啊
Interesting, you didn't mention Amy.
你觉得浇上黄油和枫糖的法式吐司是谁做的
Who do you think made the French toast with butter and syrup?
你们即将进入
You're about to enter the lab
已故大卫·萨尔兹伯格博士的实验室
of the late Dr. David Saltzberg.
他在进行延缓衰老过程的研究时
While conducting studies on slowing the aging process,
出现了灾难性事故  他不幸身亡
there was a catastrophic accident and he died.
真死了吗
Or did he?
女士优先
Ladies?
你是出于礼貌还是胆小
Are you being polite or scared?
是的
Yup.
这房间厉害啦
Ah, what a room!
真酷
This is cool.
我们该怎么开始
So, how do we start?
我们要找出藏在这房间的线索
We have to look for the clues hidden around the room.
这里不是应该有个僵尸吗
Uh, wasn't there supposed to be a zombie?
好吧  希望其中一条线索
Okay, let's hope one of the clues
是写在一条干净的裤衩上
is written on a pair of clean underwear.
沃罗威茨夫妇
Mr. And Mrs. Wolowitz?
据我所知  你们的行李已经到达洛杉矶
As far as I can tell, your bag arrived in Los Angeles.
那它在哪里
So, where is it?
我不知道  可能有人
I don't know, perhaps somebody
不小心从行李转盘上拿走了
took it off the carousel by mistake?
所以某个陌生人把我妈带走了
So, some stranger has my mom?
你是这个意思吗
Is that what you're telling me?
我可怜的母亲现在可能在洛杉矶的任何地方
My poor mother can be anywhere in Los Angeles right now?
我希望我是这个意思
I-I wish I was telling you that.
但那名乘客也可能已经坐上
Um...but the passenger could've gotten
国际航班飞走了
on an international flight.
这下可好
Oh, okay, great!
所以你的工作是寻找丢失的行李
So, your entire job is to find lost luggage,
而你帮我把我母亲的所在范围
and you've narrowed down the location
缩小到整个地球
of my mother to the planet Earth!
非常抱歉
I'm sorry!
送你们500英里飞行里程好吗
W-Would 500 frequent-flyer miles help?
可以让你们飞到萨克拉门托哦
That could get you to Sacramento.
"如果你明早一觉醒来
"If you could wake up tomorrow
发现自己获得了某种能力
having gained any one quality or ability,
你希望是什么能力"
what would it be?"
我不想山寨圣经故事
Well, not to steal from the Bible,
不过能把水变成酒[耶稣]  还是挺酷的
but turning water into wine sounds pretty good.
你完全没有严肃对待这个实验
I don't think you're taking this seriously.
我在逗你玩呢
Come on, I'm just having some fun with you.
我想你是借插科打诨
I believe what you're doing
逃避你内心的弱点
is using humor to avoid vulnerability.
好吧
Fine.
老实说
Honestly...
如果我能获得一种能力
if I could have one quality...
我希望我能像你们一样聪明
I wish I could be as smart as you guys.
哈  你就做梦吧
Ha! Keep dreaming.
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我这也是在逗你呢
That was me having fun with you.
我说
Look.
你虽然没有
You may not be as...
像我们一样有学术天赋
academically inclined as are we.
是的  这才是正确的表达方式
Yes, that's how you say it.
可是
But...
你拥有一种令我羡慕的能力
You possess an intelligence I envy.
那也是我对这个问题的答案
Which leads me to my answer.
我希望能获得
I would choose the ability
读别人心思的能力
to read people's minds.
其实我也没法读别人的心思
Well, I can't read people's minds.
其实  这话我说错了
Actually, that's not true.
我可以读到男人的心思
I can read men's minds.
但那是因为他们想的都是一件事
But only 'cause it's usually the one thing.
我们什么时候才能拥有机械人眼睛吗
When are we going to get robot eyes?
你们男人想得都一样
You're all alike.
我的意思是
Well, what I meant was...
我经常误解
I often misinterpret
别人的想法
how others are feeling.
比如  我有时会分不清别人是在开玩笑
Like, I can't always tell if someone is only joking
还是在嘲笑我
or laughing at me.
比如他们是在生我的气
You know, like, uh, if they're mad at something I've done
还是单纯情绪不佳而已
or just in a bad mood.
真是让我压力山大
It-it's incredibly stressful.
真的吗  你看起来一直很有自信啊
Really? You always seem so confident.
其实我没有
Well, I'm not.
如果我能读懂别人的心思
And if I could read people's minds,
生活应该多么轻松愉快啊
life would be so much simpler.
我现在希望我拥有能让你
Well, now I wish I had the ability
轻松读懂别人心思的能力了
to make that stuff easier for you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我刚刚心头
Wow, I just felt
涌上一股对你浓烈的感情
this wave of affection for you.
你确定不是喝多"圣经琼浆"迷糊了吗
You sure it's not too much Bible juice?
那股感情迅速退去
And the wave is gone.
我要吃大脑
Brains!
小声点  我们这儿在工作呢
Keep it down! We're working here.
我们破解了这个密码
Okay, we've got the cipher decoded!
地球仪搞定了吗
How's it going with the globe?
我们用坐标确定了城市
We used the coordinates to locate the cities.
我正在把城市名填入表格
I'm putting the city names in the grid now.
马上就能得出安全屋的口令了
I'm sure that'll give us the code to the safe.
谜题解答太迅猛
Solve puzzle too fast!
慢一点
Slow down!
好了  拿到口令了
Yup! Got the code.
我就说一声...
Just saying...
你们玩得快也不退门票哦
no refund for finish early!
你真的不想回家吗
Sure you don't want to go home?
等包裹找到了  他们会送到我们家的
When the bag's returned, they'll deliver it to us.
不  找不到她我就不走
No, I'm not leaving without her.
好吧  我们慢慢等
All right, we'll wait.
我本应该开车载她的
I could've driven her.
什么
What?
她去佛罗里达的那天
The day she left for Florida.
她让我载她去机场
She asked me to drive her to the airport.
我太忙了
I-I was too busy.
于是我让她
And...I made her
坐出租车去
take a cab.
我说自己太忙了
I was too busy.
你也意想不到嘛
There's no way you could've known.
我过去一下
Be right back.
打扰一下
Excuse me?
什么事
Yes?
你最好找到我老公的妈妈
You better find my husband's mother
因为我们离开机场时  无论如何
'cause one way or another, we're walking out of this airport
都要带走一个死女人
with a dead woman!
我们要找哪本书
Which book are we looking for?
《物种起源》
Origin of Species.
找到了
Here it is.
里面有个黑光灯
There's a black light.
等一下
Oh, hang on.
好了
Oh, okay.
"我没有兄弟姐妹
Uh, "Brothers and sisters I have none,
但这个人的父亲是我父亲的儿子
but this man's father is my father's son.
请问这个人是谁"
Who am I looking at?"
好了  我们知道你想吃大脑
Yeah, yeah, we get it-- you want brains.
别闹
Calm down.
如果我没有兄弟
Well, if I don't have a brother,
那我父亲的儿子就是我自己了
my father's son is me.
如果我是这个人的父亲  那他就是我儿子
And if I'm this man's father, then he's my son.
答案是儿子
The answer's "son."
那里有一张太阳的照片[同音]
Ooh! There's a picture of the sun over there.
钥匙一定在后面
I bet the key's behind it.
也可能不在后面哦
Could be somewhere else!
找到钥匙了
Oh, got the key!
所以这就是开门的钥匙了吗
So, that's the key to the door?
就这样完了吗
That's it?
我们花了200大洋  就玩了6分钟而已
We spent $200 on six minutes of fun?
感觉就像是你买的那台遥控直升机
It's like when you bought that remote-controlled helicopter,
结果就...飞走了
and it just... flew away.
对不起了各位
Sorry, guys.
我本以为谜题会更难一点呢
Really thought the puzzles would be better.
说句公道话  我们都是有高等学历的人
Well, to be fair, we do all have advanced degrees.
网上点评的时候别忘了说这句哦
Remember that before you post on Yelp!
"如果你将在今晚死去  没有任何
"If you were to die this evening with no opportunity
再与他人交流的机会
to communicate with anyone,
你最后悔没有把什么事情跟别人说"
what would you most regret not having told someone?"
那就是今天
So, it would be today?
在生日这天死亡
Well, I suppose there's something satisfying
也还算是某种满足吧
about dying on my birthday.
今天是你生日吗
Today's your birthday?
是的
Yes.
你一直都当秘密没说
Well, that's always been a secret!
连艾米都不知道
Not even Amy knows!
因为我不喜欢收礼物
Well, I don't enjoy presents.
以及想到一大堆人
And the thought of people
蹦出来大喊"惊喜"
jumping out and yelling "Surprise!"
比"乔治·卢卡斯导演剪辑版"
fills me with more dread than the words
更让我身怀恐惧
"George Lucas Director's Cut."
那你为什么又对我说了
So, why did you finally tell me?
这个实验的重点就是
The point of the experiment is
对彼此绝对坦诚
to be completely honest with each other.
谢谢你愿意告诉我
Well, thank you for sharing it with me.
我不会说出去的
I won't tell anyone.
谢谢
Thank you.
太好玩了
That is so funny.
我从来没想过你居然是双鱼座
I never would have pegged you for a Pisces.
你在增加我爱上你的难度
You're making it difficult to love you right now.
好消息  你们的行李还回来了
Great news! Your bag was returned.
感谢老天爷
Oh, thank God!
好了  她在
It's okay, she's here!
妈在这
Ma's here.
非常感谢你
Okay, thank you so much.
妈
Ma?
对不起  我没有送你去机场
I'm sorry I didn't take you to the airport.
希望你能知道
I just want you to know
我永远都不会原谅自己的自私行为
that I'll never forgive myself for being so selfish.
我保证
And I promise
有生之年
to keep you close
都会把你留在身边
for the rest of my life.
亲娘的  这玩意要被摆到卧室了
Oh, no. That thing's gonna end up in my bedroom.
没有了  问题都答完了
That's it! We're done with the questions.
只剩下彼此凝视四分钟
All that's left to do is stare into each other's eyes
不许说话
for four minutes without talking.
好
Okay.
等一下
Wait, hang on!
膀胱检查
Bladder check.
可以开始了
We're good to go.
准备
You ready?
好
Yes.
现在开始
And begin.
这样有点怪啊
This is kind of creepy.
这段期间我们不应该说话
We're not supposed to talk during this part.
对不起
Sorry.
这样有点怪啊
This is kind of creepy.
想停吗
Do you want to stop?
我知道你不喜欢目光交流
I know you have trouble with eye contact.
你右眼虹膜上有个棕色小斑点
Well, you have a brown fleck in your right iris
像一辆一级方程式赛车
that looks like a Formula One race car.
所以  我就盯着它看好了
So... I'm just concentrating on that.
而且和处着舒服的人在一起
Plus, it's easier around people
已经简单很多了
that I'm comfortable with.
亲爱的  和你相处也很舒服
Aw, sweetie, I'm comfortable around you, too.
当然  我是如此温暖的可人儿
Of course you are, I'm warm and soothing.
简直是一碗人形番茄汤
I'm like a human bowl of tomato soup.
我是说把你当弟弟一样看
I meant more like a little brother.
其实我真会把你当姐姐
Well, I suppose I do think of you as a sister.
有时候当妈妈
And sometimes, a mother.
感觉又变怪了
It's getting creepy again.
怎么了
What?
想到了第一天见到你和莱纳德
Just thinking about the day I met you and Leonard.
那是周一下午
It was a Monday afternoon.
你来和我们一起吃印度餐
You joined us for Indian food.
真不敢相信已经八年了
Can you believe it's been eight years?
你还在蹭我们的饭
Yeah, and you're still eating our food.
我...都记不起
I... can't remember a time
没有你们的生活是怎样的了
you guys weren't in my life.
我记得一清二楚
I remember it perfectly.
因为我过目不忘
But I have an eidetic memory.
如果你感兴趣
If you're interested, I also remember
我还记得你总共欠我们多少饭钱
how much you owe us for the food.
时间到了
That's it.
还不算太糟
That wasn't so bad.
真不算
No, it wasn't.
现在我们来整理一下试验结果
Uh, now let's tabulate the results of the experiment.
可以放心地说出  你没有爱上我
I think it's safe to say that you're not in love with me
我也没有爱上你
and I'm not in love with you.
而心理学再次自证了
And psychology has once again
自己是科学中的蠢货
proved itself the doofus of the sciences.
也许吧
Well, maybe.
但我还是很开心我们做了这个
But I'm still glad we did it.
感觉和你更亲近了
I do feel closer to you.
彼此彼此
And I, you.
是的  这才是正确的表达方式
And yes, that's how you say that.
考虑到我们新建立的亲密度
Yeah, so, given our newfound intimacy,
有很多难以抉择的问题得做决定
I'd say we have some hard choices to make.
比如什么
Like what?
加里大会  我们开车去还是搭飞机
Gary Con-- do we fly or drive?
扮还是不扮人物
Do we wear costumes?
如果扮
And if so...
谁来扮加里
who gets to be Gary?
谢谢你送我回家
Thank you for walking me home.
只是想看你安全到家
I just want to make sure you get there safe.
好了  我到家了
Well, this is me.
今晚过得真有趣
It's been a very interesting evening.
确实如此
It really has.
惊喜
Surprise!
我都让你扮加里了还这样
And after I let you be Gary!